What a beautiful man.
好美的人啊
Are you the new fiancée?
妳就是新來的未婚妻嗎?
Yes.
是的
Remember, while you're here you must absolutely follow my orders.
聽好了,在這裡要完全遵從我的命令
If I tell you to leave, you leave.
我叫妳出去,妳就得出去
If I tell you to die, you die.
我叫妳去死,妳就得去死
I won't listen to any complaints or objections.
我不接受抱怨和反駁
Yes, sir.
遵命
Huh?
什麼?
Is there anything else?
請問還有其他吩咐嗎?
I look forward to living here with you.
還請多多關照
My new life with Kiyoka Kudo started this way in a quiet fashion.
我與久堂清霞先生的新生活 就這樣安靜地拉開序幕
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
我的幸福婚約
EPISODE 2 ABOUT MY HUSBAND-TO-BE
第 2 集 劇名:關於老爺這個人
Please use this room, Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐請使用這間房間吧
Thank you for your kind consideration.
謝謝妳為我考慮這麼多
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐
Yes?
什麼事?
I'm aware of the bad rumors about Young Master,
雖然少爺在外面好像 有很多不好聽的傳聞
but actually, he is a kind man.
但他其實是個溫柔的人
Well, I'll excuse myself now.
那麼我就先告退了
Thank you, Ms. Yurie.
好的,謝謝妳
These are high-grade futons.
高級的棉被
I thought he'd be more abusive or treat me with contempt.
還以為老爺對我會有更多咒罵或蔑視
I was even ready to be abruptly thrown out of the house.
我甚至做好會突然 被趕出去的心理準備
Because I'm from the Saimori family, he probably thinks
因為我是齋森家的女兒
that I have supernatural abilities.
所以他肯定以為我有異能
If so...
如果是這樣...
Now, I'm going to test you to see if you have Spirit-Sight.
現在開始測試 妳們兩人是否有見鬼之才
Miyo, Kaya, sharpen your senses.
美世、香耶,讓妳們的感官變敏銳些
- Yes.
-是
I'm opening it.
那麼我要打開了
Ah! Stay away.
啊,不要過來!
Kaya!
香耶!
No! Don't come near me!
不要啊,不要過來這邊!
If you were able to see the Grotesqueries, you have Spirit-Sight!
能夠看見異形就表示妳有見鬼之才!
You'll also gain supernatural abilities one day. Good job, Kaya!
未來妳的異能一定也會開花結果 做得非常好,香耶!
Supernatural abilities?
“異能”?
How nice.
天啊
So you're able to see even more now?
從那之後妳看得更清楚了嗎?
Yesterday, I was able to move the shiki-gami a bit.
我昨天還成功讓式神稍微移動了喔
Wasn't I a good girl?
我很棒對吧?
Of course, she has talent. We are Kaya's birth parents, after all.
不愧是真一先生跟我生的女兒
She isn't like that good-for-nothing who can't use Spirit-Sight at all.
跟那個到現在 還跟見鬼沾不上邊的飯桶差多了
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐
It'll be all right.
妳一定沒問題的
I know what terrible things they say about me behind my back.
我知道大家在背地裡 都把我說得很難聽
I'm useless because I don't have supernatural abilities.
沒有異能的我是個沒用的人
Ms. Miyo...
美世小姐...
That must mean I'm not wanted here just like Mother's cherry tree.
我肯定和那棵母親大人的櫻花樹一樣 是不被需要的孩子對吧?
A dream.
那是夢
Oh yes, I don't live in that house anymore.
對喔,我已經不在那個家了
I have to make myself useful in this house.
我得在這個家好好派上用場才行
Oh my, something smells good.
哎呀,好香的味道
It looks good.
感覺做得不錯
Ms. Miyo.
美世小姐?
Ms. Yurie, good morning.
由里江小姐,早安
Good morning, Ms. Miyo.
早安,美世小姐
You just got here, and you're already making a meal this early in the morning?
您才剛搬來不久 竟然一大清早就在準備早餐
Um, I'm sorry I didn't ask for permission.
那個,我自作主張了,很抱歉
Please don't mention it!
怎麼會呢?千萬別這樣說!
You are Young Master's fiancée.
畢竟美世小姐是少爺的未婚妻啊
It looks delicious! I'm sure Young Master will appreciate it.
天啊,看起來真美味 少爺一定也會很開心的
Preparing meals is my job, but as you can see
雖然準備餐點是我的工作 但是就如您所見
I'm getting to be an old wrinkled grandma.
我已經是滿臉皺紋的老太婆了
I'm really grateful that you are helping me.
您願意幫忙,真的幫了我很大的忙
I-I'm glad to.
不,別客氣
Well, since there's still time before Young Master wakes up,
那麼,少爺還要過一會兒才會起床
I should go do other things now.
我先把其他工作完成吧
Ms. Miyo, can I leave breakfast up to you?
美世小姐,這裡交給您可以嗎?
Yes, if it's all right with you.
好的,如果妳不嫌棄的話
Good morning, Young Master.
早安啊,少爺
Good morning.
早安
Yurie, stop calling me Young Master in front of others.
由里江,別在其他人 面前叫我“少爺”了
Good morning, sir.
早安,老爺
Young Master, Ms. Miyo prepared breakfast this morning.
少爺,今天早上 美世小姐幫忙做了早餐喔
- She did? - Oh, yes.
-是嗎? -是啊
She was very skilled. It was helpful for me.
她的廚藝非常精練,幫了我很多
Sit over here.
妳坐這邊
Y-Yes.
是
You try it first.
妳先吃吃看
Pardon?
什麼?
You can't eat it?
妳吃不下去嗎?
Uh... Well...
不,那個...
Did you put poison in it?
妳是不是下毒了?
How transparent.
還真是顯而易見
Poison?
下毒?
I can't eat this because I don't know what's inside it.
我不吃這種 裡面不知道放了什麼的料理
Put it away.
把餐點收走
Try harder next time.
下次用更高明的方法吧
Wait, Young Master?
等一下,少爺?
Young Master!
少爺!
Although my intentions were good, it turned out to be a massive failure.
我好意採取的行動 卻招致意料之外的重大失敗
SPECIAL ANTI-GROTESQUERIE UNIT
(對異特殊部隊)
I welcome you to the Special Anti-Grotesquerie Unit.
各位,歡迎你們加入對異特殊部隊
Through rigorous discipline, I expect you to heighten your supernatural abilities.
我希望你們藉由嚴峻的訓練 磨練自己的異能,精進自己的技術
Supernatural abilities are a potential that lies in your spirit.
“異能”是潛藏在靈魂中的力量
Telekinesis, pyrokinesis, clairvoyance.
念動力、起火能力、透視能力
Supernatural abilities do not go against the rules of nature of this world.
無論是何種異能 都不會偏離這個世界的法則
They are the embodiment of the power of the spirit.
是將靈魂之力具現化的能力
And Grotesqueries have been living in this nation from ancient times.
然後自古以來 就有異形棲息在這個國家
Often called demons or spirits, they are harmful to humans.
異形亦被稱為鬼或妖怪 是對人類有害的存在
The one and only power to fight them off is your supernatural ability.
當異形出現時,唯一能夠 對抗其威脅的特殊能力正是異能
So where are these Grotesqueries?
所以最關鍵的異形到底在哪啊?
Why train if we're never called to fight?
不管我們做多少準備 沒機會出動就沒意義了嘛
That is why we need to prepare for them so whenever they show up... Huh?
因此我們隨時隨地都要準備好 面對出沒的異形...怎麼了?
- Whoa! - Uh.
-哇! -啊
- Oh. - Ahh...
-哇 -天啊
With the passage of time, the number of Grotesqueries have diminished.
隨著時代變遷,異形的數量銳減
So now, we are rarely mobilized to eradicate them.
如今討伐異形的任務也寥寥無幾
That's why serious damage and confusion are assumed to occur from such incidents.
正因為如此,一旦發生狀況時 極有可能造成巨大的傷亡及混亂
I expect you to be ready to take the lead and fight the Grotesqueries
各位必須擔任先鋒與異形戰鬥
when the time comes.
期待你們都有強大的覺悟
- Yes, sir!
-是!
Come in.
進來
Commander, I've brought the papers you asked for.
隊長,我把你交代的文件拿來了
I noticed you were exceptionally fired up for that newcomer training.
剛才訓練新人時,你特別起勁呢
Oh? Not in a good mood today?
奇怪?你今天心情不好嗎?
Can you hear me? Hello? Commander Kudo?
有聽見嗎?喂,久堂隊長
Hmm? Could it be that another fiancée has fled your house--
怎麼了啊?該不會是 未婚妻又跑了吧...
Stop yapping and get out of here already.
少說廢話,快點出去
I nailed it, didn't I?
該不會被我說中了吧?
Do you want to be burned?
你這麼想被我用火烤嗎?
Oops. You seem especially irritable today.
糟糕,看來你今天心情特別差啊
Well then. If you would excuse me.
那麼我就先告退了
Young Master, are you listening?
少爺,您有在聽嗎?
Yeah, I hear you.
有,我有在聽
You really shouldn't have treated her in that way.
您何必把話說得那麼難聽呢?
Ms. Miyo made a serious effort to prepare a meal for you.
美世小姐真的努力地準備了料理
I can't imagine her putting poison in your food.
我不認為她是會下毒的那種人
It's rare for Yurie to defend someone to that extent.
由里江竟然會幫她說話 到那種程度,還真是難得
I can't believe I'm thinking about this. I must concentrate more on my work.
真是的,我竟然在想別的事 未免也太散漫了
I can't believe I made such a blunder so soon after moving in.
我才來這裡不久馬上就犯錯了
If the rumors about my husband-to-be are true, maybe I can't stay here anymore.
如果老爺真的如傳聞一樣 我大概就不能繼續待在這間屋子了
Your room is ready, Koji.
我幫幸次準備好房間了
From today, use it as you like.
從今天起你可以自由使用
Thank you very much.
多謝費心
You need to start preparing to enter this family.
你也得開始準備入贅儀式吧?
The days ahead might get busy. I expect your best efforts.
接下來應該會變得忙碌,就交給你了
Y-Yes.
好的
Where should we move this?
請問這些行李要搬去哪裡呢?
Move it into my sister's room, please.
都拿去姊姊的房間吧
Good evening, Kaya.
晚安,香耶
Oh, it's you, Koji.
哎呀,這不是幸次先生嗎?
I can move that for you, if you'd like.
那些行李不如讓我來搬吧
It must be heavy.
應該很重吧
You're kind to other servants too, not just Big Sister. It's so like you.
對姊姊以外的傭人也這麼溫柔 不愧是幸次先生呢
Miyo lived in a room like this?
美世竟然住在這種地方?
If Miyo is thrown out of the Kudo family with nowhere to go,
如果美世被久堂家趕出家門 然後流落街頭的話
I want to be the one who she feels safe with.
到時候我就必須成為美世的歸宿才行
Hey, Koji!
話說回來,幸次先生
Can I ask you to move this too?
這個也可以拜託你嗎?
Yeah, I'll be right there.
好,我馬上過去
There must be something only I can do.
一定有什麼事情是只有我才能做到的
Welcome home, sir.
歡迎回家,老爺
I...
那個...
What is it?
什麼事?
I want to apologize for this morning.
今天早上非常抱歉
I overstepped my position.
我做出了踰矩的行為
A man of your status couldn't possibly eat something prepared by one you don't trust.
以老爺的立場來說 不可能食用不信賴的人所做的料理
I should have known better.
我應該要思慮得更周全
Everything for supper tonight was prepared by Ms. Yurie.
今天的晚餐全都是 由里江小姐所製作的餐點
On my word, I put no poison in it.
我發誓絕對沒有下毒
Please--
請您務必...
It wasn't that I seriously suspected you.
我並不是真心懷疑妳
I just didn't feel like eating food prepared by a stranger.
我只是不想吃陌生人所做的料理
I'm truly sorry.
真的非常抱歉
It's cold.
都冷掉了
I'm sorry.
對不起
You don't have to apologize for that.
這不是妳需要道歉的事
It seems you keep apologizing as if it's natural to do so. Why?
妳似乎習慣經常道歉,這是為什麼?
- You're not answering me, are you? - I'm sorry--
-妳不願意說嗎? -對不...
Don't apologize.
別再道歉了
If you apologize too much, it loses its meaning.
道歉過度就會變得沒有分量
Did you eat yet?
晚餐呢?妳已經吃過了嗎?
Uh, well I...
那個,我...
Why didn't you make a meal for yourself?
妳為什麼沒有準備自己的份?
Yurie went home already, right?
由里江已經回家了吧?
Yes.
是的
Didn't Yurie make a meal for you too?
難道由里江沒有準備妳的餐點?
That's not it.
不是這樣的
I didn't have an appetite, so I told her that I didn't need anything.
因為我沒有食慾 所以請由里江小姐不用幫我準備
Are you not feeling well?
妳身體不舒服嗎?
Don't mind me. It's nothing.
不,我沒什麼大礙
All right. As you wish.
好吧,隨便妳
I'm done.
我吃飽了
Um, then I'll get the bath ready--
那個,我馬上去燒洗澡水...
I'll do it myself.
我自己來就好
But...
可是...
I always do it myself.
我一直以來也都是自己燒水
Instead of making a fire to heat up the water,
因為比起刻意燒柴煮水
it's easier if I use my supernatural ability to get hot water.
我自己用異能來燒水還比較省事
Don't try to do unnecessary things.
妳不必做多餘的事情
Since I don't have supernatural abilities, I can't even draw a bath in this house.
沒有異能的我在這個家 連燒洗澡水都辦不到
I... am not useful for anything.
我真的是一無用處也沒有
Do you have a minute?
可以稍微跟妳說些話嗎?
Y-Yes.
當然可以
Sorry for not eating your breakfast today.
今天早餐一口都沒吃,抱歉
Yurie said she'll be a little late tomorrow morning.
明天早上由里江似乎會晚點到
You're in charge of breakfast tomorrow.
明天的早餐就拜託妳做了
Oh, me?
讓我來嗎?
If you really attempt to put poison in it, you're done.
但妳若是真的下毒 我是不會饒過妳的
Of course, I won't!
我怎麼敢呢
No problem, then.
那沒問題吧?
No problem, sir.
沒問題
The bath is still hot. You should go in before it gets cold.
洗澡水還是熱的 趁冷掉之前快點去洗澡吧
Uh, um...
等一下,那個...
Thank you... very much.
真的很感謝你
I couldn't properly thank him.
我沒能好好向他道謝
I'm aware of the bad rumors about Young Master,
雖然少爺在外面好像 有很多不好聽的傳聞
but actually, he is a kind man.
但他其實是個溫柔的人
He gave me a chance to make up for my failure.
好不容易從老爺那裡獲得的機會
I really can't mess it up tomorrow.
我明天絕對不可以失敗
Hana!
阿花!
Ms. Miyo, what's the matter?
美世大小姐,怎麼了嗎?
They're gone! Heirlooms from Mother, her cherry blossom kimono... All gone!
全都不見了!母親大人的遺物 還有她櫻粉色的和服都沒在這裡!
What? Why in the world...?
怎麼會?到底是為什麼?
It must be Stepmom Kanoko.
一定是香乃子小姐拿的
I'll go and get them back.
我要去找她要回母親大人的遺物
But if you confront her alone, there's no telling what she'll do.
不行啊,大小姐一個人去 不知道她會做出什麼事
It'll be all right. I'll tell Father if anything happens.
不要緊,萬一出事我會跟父親大人說
You sure are the daughter of that conniving thief.
不愧是那隻狐狸精生的女兒
Accusing me of stealing? Your attitude is unbelievably rotten.
竟然說我是小偷 性格再差也要有個底線吧
What rubbish.
這種爛東西
You still had this, huh?
妳還帶在身上啊?
No, don't!
住手!
That's Mother's--
那是母親大人的...
Think about what you did. Don't show your face until you're sorry.
在妳反省認錯之前 不許妳出現在我面前
Close the door.
把門關上
Let me out! Somebody! Father!
不要,讓我出去 誰來幫幫我啊,父親大人!
Father!
父親大人!
Mrs. Saimori, Mr. Saimori, please don't!
夫人、主人,請不要這樣!
Silence!
給我閉嘴!
Who do you think you are? Servant!
妳不過是個傭人,少自以為是了!
But it's cruel to Ms. Miyo...
這樣美世小姐實在太...
Hana...
阿花
You know what happens when you challenge me, don't you?
妳應該知道頂撞我會有什麼下場吧?
Let me out...
放我出去
Somebody, help me...
誰快來救救我
Again. A bad dream.
又是討厭的惡夢
I wonder what Hana is doing now?
阿花現在不知道過得如何?
After she was fired because of that day, I never met her even once.
自從那天的事發生後 阿花就被解僱,我從此沒再見過她
I hope she is happy and doing well.
希望她能過得幸福快樂
This is also nearing the end of its life.
這件和服的壽命也差不多了
Oh, Ms. Miyo. Good morning.
哎呀,是美世小姐,您早啊
Ms. Yurie?
由里江小姐?
I see you're up pretty early today, too.
您今天早上也很早起呢
Yes. Um, weren't you going to be late today?
是的,話說妳今天不是會晚點到嗎?
Well, I came early today because I was concerned about what happened yesterday.
這個嘛,因為昨天早上發生那樣的事 我有點在意,所以今天提早過來
I'll take care of breakfast, so why don't you relax in the living room?
早餐就由我來準備 美世小姐就去起居室放鬆一下吧
Well, actually...
其實,關於那件事...
Oh my, is that what Young Master said?
天啊,少爺也真是的
If he wanted to eat your cooking, he should have said so.
既然想吃美世小姐親手做的料理 直接說就好了嘛
Well, I don't think that's what this is about...
不,我想應該不是那樣
But I'm just not so sure of myself.
但是我有點沒自信
Then Ms. Miyo, why don't you let me help you?
那麼美世小姐,就讓我來協助您吧
Oh, please do.
好的,麻煩了
I wonder if this is the right flavor...
這味道可以嗎?
- That's beautiful. - I make it all the time.
-好漂亮 -我經常在做嘛
So I'm used to making it fast. But, there's no guarantee of the taste.
我只是做得很快 但不能保證味道如何喔
It looks delicious.
看起來很美味
As a servant, it's an honor to hear a compliment from a good cook like you.
被擅長料理的美世小姐如此稱讚 作為一個傭人真是萬分榮幸呢
Will he really eat this meal prepared by someone like me?
我這種人做的料理 老爺真的會願意吃嗎?
This is my last chance.
我已經沒有退路了
Now, Young Master should be getting up soon.
走吧,少爺差不多要起床了
Would you please bring the breakfast to the other room?
請把早餐端過去
Certainly.
好的
Good morning.
早安
Good morning, sir.
早安,老爺
Well, let's eat.
那麼我開動了
You should eat too.
妳也得一起吃
I-I'm sor...
非常抱...
I mean...
沒事
I will eat too.
我開動了
It's good.
真好喝
It tastes a little different from how Yurie makes it, but not bad.
雖然跟由里江的調味 有些許不同,不過還不錯
Oh, thank you very much.
謝謝誇獎
Why are you crying?
為什麼有必要哭?
I-I'm sorry...
非常抱歉...
I told you not to apologize.
我說過了,不要道歉
Yes, sir.
好的
When was the last time I was praised, or accepted by someone like this?
我已經多久沒有像這樣 被人稱讚與認同了呢?
Her background is a mystery.
我看不出她成長的背景
She wears such rags that can't even be called old clothes.
連舊衣都稱不上的破舊和服
Her body is so thin that she must have had a troubled life.
身體消瘦到讓人覺得 她日常生活肯定出了什麼問題
Her hands look so worn from housework. Is she really from a prominent family?
煮飯洗衣的人才會有的粗糙雙手 實在不像是出自名門的大小姐
Yurie.
由里江
Maybe she wasn't raised as a typical daughter from a prominent family.
她會不會是沒被當成 一般的名門大小姐來撫養?
I know what you mean. Yes.
我懂您的意思,確實如此
Do you think she would tell us if we asked her?
妳覺得我問她原因,她會回答嗎?
That might be difficult.
應該很困難吧
You should discreetly keep an eye on her.
妳暗中留意一下吧
I'll do what I can to look into the Saimori family.
我會從外面稍微調查齋森家
Very well.
我明白了
How unusual, Young Master. You seem to be interested in this fiancée.
話說回來,少爺這次一反常態 對這位未婚妻很有興趣呢
Interested?
有興趣?
You know, Ms. Miyo might not like you if you can't express your true feelings.
您也知道,如果不坦率表達情感 會被美世小姐討厭的喔
She can dislike me all she wants.
她要討厭的話就讓她討厭吧
Most of the women who came here were after wealth or status from the start.
說到過去的訂婚對象,幾乎所有女人 最初目的就是金錢和權力
I think Ms. Miyo will be a fine wife for you, Young Master.
我覺得美世小姐 非常適合當少爺的妻子喔
Why do you seem so sure?
妳說得還真是斬釘截鐵
Anyway, I'm counting on you.
總之就拜託妳了
Leave it up to me.
包在我身上
The Saimori family...
齋森家啊...
There aren't a lot of bloodlines with supernatural abilities.
擁有異能的家族並不多
I hope there won't be bad news that comes out.
希望不要挖出什麼麻煩的實情
Hey! What are you doing breaking your promise?
喂!你將我們之間的 約定作廢是什麼意思?
Don't you understand the value that girl has?
難道你不明白那女孩的價值嗎?
What are you talking about?
哪來什麼約定?
Miyo is none of your business.
關於美世的事情 你沒有資格對我說三道四
Stop messing around! You made a firm promise that Miyo,
開什麼玩笑! 我們當初明明約好了,美世她...
who has the blood of the Usuba family, will be given to the Tatsuishi family!
那個繼承薄刃之血的女孩 要由我們辰石家來接收!
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Ohno
字幕翻譯:盧慧文